<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="app_name">Mandelbrot Maps</string>
	<string name="main_title">Mandelbrot Maps</string>
	<string name="continue_label">Continue</string>
	<string name="fractal_label">Fractal - single thread</string>
	<string name="bitmap_test_label">Fractal - dual threads</string>
	<string name="exit_label">Exit</string>
	
	<string name="settings_label">Settings...</string>
	<string name="settings_title">Mandelbrot Maps settings</string>
	<string name="settings_shortcut">s</string>
	
	<string name="mmaps_title">Mandelbrot Maps</string>
	
	<string name="detail_title">Detail</string>
	
   	<string name="about_text">\
	An Android port of Mandelbrot Maps,
	currently capable of displaying and
	moving a Mandelbrot fractal. 
	</string>
	
	<string name="intro_text">
	<![CDATA[
	<h2>Welcome to <span style="font-style: italic;">Mandelbrot Maps</span>!</h2>
	<p>This app is designed to showcase the relationship between the Mandelbrot set and Julia set fractals.
	<p>Move around the fractals with one finger and pinch to zoom. When you zoom, the fractal will re-render with more detail.
	<p>Hold your finger on a point in the Mandelbrot or select <b>Add Julia</b> from the menu to display a Julia fractal.
	There\'s a unique Julia fractal for each point in the Mandelbrot set - change the point defining it by dragging the coloured pin. Tap it to 
	see it in more detail.
	<p><b>Mandelbrot Maps</b> is being developed as my undergraduate dissertation project, so any feedback you leave on the Google Play Store page
	is greatly appreciated.
	<p><b>Mandelbrot Maps</b> is open-source software, relased under the GNU General Public License (v3). The source code can be
	found <a href="https://github.com/withad/Mandelbrot-Maps-on-Android">here</a>.
	]]>
	</string>
	
	<string name="help_text">
	<![CDATA[
	<h1>About fractals</h1>
	<p>A fractal is a \"self-similar\" shape, meaning that the same detailed pattern repeats over and over again as you zoom in. In the Mandelbrot
	set fractal, for example, those distinctive heart-shaped bulbs will keep appearing.
	<p>Fractals are generated by iterating a mathematical function on a set of points. Doing more iterations takes a longer time but produces
	more detailed shapes. More iterations have to be done when zooming in, to keep the same level of apparent detail. 
	<h1>About the Mandelbrot and Julia sets</h1>
	<p>Probably the most recgonisable fractal of them all, the Mandelbrot set was discovered and popularised by mathematician Benoit Mandelbrot,
	who also invented the term \"fractal\" to describe the shapes he studied. It was one of the first fractals to be visualised on a computer,
	on March 1st, 1980, in IBM\'s Thomas J. Watson Research Centre. 
	<p>Julia sets are an older idea, first researched in the early 20th century by Gaston Julia. When a Julia set is defined using the same
	function that defines the Mandelbrot set, some very interesting behaviour appears. If the Julia set is parametirised by a point inside the
	Mandelbrot set, it will be connected. Moving out of the Mandelbrot set causes the Julia fractal to break apart into unconnected pieces.
	<p>The Mandelbrot and Julia sets also look similar in certain regions, particularly on the borders of the Mandelbrot. It is these relationships
	that <b>Mandelbrot Maps</b> was developed to demonstrate.
	
	<h1>Controls</h1>
	<p>Drag with a single finger to move around the fractals. Any new areas will fill themselves in once you stop.
	<p>Use two fingers to zoom in and out. Again, the fractal will re-render once you stop.
	<p>To compare the Mandelbrot and Julia sets, long click a point in the Mandelbrot set or tap <b>Add Julia</b> on the menu. Drag the coloured 
	circle around to change the point parametirising the Julia set. To see the fractal in more detail, tap it. The zoom level and region 
	displayed will stay constant as you swap between the two fractals. Tap <b>Reset</b> on the menu to return to the default area. Dismiss the small
	fractal by tapping <b>Remove Julia/Mandelbrot</b> on the menu. If you lose track of the Julia pin, long click again or add and remove the 
	Julia from the menu to bring it to you.
	
	<h1>Other Menu Options</h1>
	<p>Under <b>Preferences</b>, you can choose the colouring scheme for each fractal, the colour of the Julia pin, whether or not to do an initial
	crude rendering (a blockier first pass that gives a faster first impression but takes slightly longer overall), and whether or not to show
	the time for each render after it\'s complete. 
	<p>Tap <b>Detail level</b> to control the level of detail on each fractal. Higher detail means more iterations will be done when rendering, 
	taking longer but giving a clearer picture.
	<p><b>Save/Share</b> lets you save an image of the current fractal into your Pictures folder or share it using email, Facebook, Twitter, etc.
	(if you have those apps installed).
	
	<h1>About Mandelbrot Maps</h1>
	<p><b>Mandelbrot Maps</b> is being developed as my undergraduate dissertation project, so any feedback you leave on the Google Play Store page
	is greatly appreciated. If you find any bugs, please include as much detail as possible, such as the device you\'re using, what you were
	doing when the error occurred, and what version of Android you\'re running. 
	<p><b>Mandelbrot Maps</b> is open-source software, relased under the GNU General Public License (v3). The source code is linked from
	the Google Play Store page.
	]]>
	</string>

	<string name="about_label">About</string>
	<string name="bitmap_label">Bitmap (not implemented)</string>
	<string name="side_by_side_label">Side-by-side fractals</string>
</resources>
